(結野)あの…｡
ん？
もう いっそ天気はいいから➡
ありがた迷惑だ｡
いいんです｡
当たり台予報とか
やってくんねえかな｡
さっきまで
あんなに機嫌よかったのに…｡
(結野)使ってください｡
え？
私なんか 風邪ひいたって…｡
よかねえよ｡
おい 何やってんだ ｱﾝﾀ！
(結野)いいんです｡
(銀時)女心と秋の空？
よろしかったら 入ります？
私が悪いんですから｡
悪いって何が？
傘 お忘れになったんですか？
え？ いや でも悪いし…｡
結野ｱﾅ 最近 天気予報調子悪いな｡
ﾊﾟﾁﾝｺ台の機嫌と秋の空
の間違いだろ｡
ちょっ… ちょっと！
待てよ 姉ちゃん！
悪いのは天気であって
ｱﾝﾀじゃねえだろ｡
それを言うなら
天気予報外した…｡
A woman's heart is as changeable
as the autumn sky?
Pachinko's luck is as changeable
as the autumn sky is more like it.
I was doing so well a moment ago.
そうです｡ 天気予報を外した
この私が悪いんです｡
Ms. Ketsuno, Ana, has been off with
her weather forecasts lately.
Maybe she should give up on the weather
and do forecasts for gambling luck.
けっ けっ けっ…｡
[ﾓﾆﾀ]今日は晴れで～す｡
結野… ｱﾅ…｡
Excuse me...
Did you forget your umbrella?
Would you like to share mine?
But I'd feel bad.
Please use this.
Hey!
Hold on!
Wait up, lady.
Hey, what are you doing?
It doesn't matter if I catch a cold.
It matters. Leave a bad
taste in my mouth.
It doesn't matter.
Since this is my fault.
What's your fault?
The weather's to blame, not you.
Hell, you might as well blame
the weather forecaster...
That's right.
It's my fault for giving an
inaccurate forecast.
K-K-Ke...
It'll be sunny today!
Ketsuno... Ana?!
["Not Losing to the Rain"]
[ﾓﾆﾀ](草野)百発百中の天気予報で
朝の顔として➡
The incredibly popular morning personality
with her dead-on forecasts,
絶大な人気を博していた
お天気お姉さん➡
weather lady Ketsuno has been
feeling under the weather.
結野ｱﾅの ここにきての不調｡
After rattling off inaccurate
forecasts lately,
最近 天気予報を外し倒し➡
Ms. Christel Ketsuno has received
a multitude of complaints,
視聴者からの苦情が殺到していた
結野ｸﾘｽﾃﾙｱﾅ｡
ついに
『おめざめﾃﾚﾋﾞ』降板という➡
and she has finally stepped down
from her position on Wake Up TV.
事態になってしまった
わけですが… どうでしょう｡
What do you think?
やっぱり 彼女のやり方に
ﾑﾘがあったと思うんだよね ﾎﾞｸは｡
I knew that there was something
wrong with her methods.
この科学の時代に
占いで天気を予測するなんて➡
It's nonsense to rely on fortune telling in this
age of science to forecast the weather.
ﾅﾝｾﾝｽ極まりないよ｡
But I believe that her popularity was
not only because of her personality,
しかし彼女が ここまでの人気を
得るに至ったのは➡
そのｷｬﾗｸﾀｰ性もさることながら
占いという➡
but because of the factor of uncertainty which comes
with using fortune telling to forecast the weather.
不確定なもので天気を
言い当ててきたところも➡
大きいと思います｡
実際 彼女の担当する➡
In fact, her black horoscopes were
known for their accuracy.
ﾌﾞﾗｯｸ星座占いなども
よく当たると評判でしたし➡
聞くところによれば 彼女
幕府開闢以来➡
Rumor has it that since the dawn of the Bakufu, her
family has served and protected them as On...
江戸を護ってきた
幕府お抱えのおん…｡
You idiots!
ﾊﾞｯｷｬﾛｰ！ お客様が来たときは➡
I told you to turn off the TV
when we have guests!
ﾃﾚﾋﾞ消せって
あれほど 言っただろうが！
You're the one who always
keeps it on, Gin-chan!
(神楽)銀ちゃんだって いっつも
お構いなしで つけてたｱﾙ！
Gin-chan? Who's that?
銀ちゃん？ 誰それ？
ｱｲﾂなら もう とっくに➡
He was killed in action long ago.
殉職しただろうが｡ ｱｲﾂのことは
もう忘れろって言ってんだ｡
I told you to forget about him already!
Bring us some tea, fool!
茶でもくんでこい｡ ﾊﾞｰﾛｰ！
(神楽)ちぇ～…｡
Boo.
すみません｡
何か ﾊﾞﾀﾊﾞﾀしちゃってて… ﾊﾊ｡
Sorry about all the chaos.
ﾎﾝﾄは 彼らの他に
20数名従業員がいるんですがね➡
I actually have another twenty
or so employees.
They're all out working today so I've only
got dead weight to work with here.
今日は 出払ってて
ﾀﾞﾒなﾔﾂしか残ってないみたいで｡
近々 六本木ﾋﾙｽﾞに
移転が決まってて➡
We're moving to Roppongi Hills soon.
それで ちょっと
ﾜﾀﾜﾀしててね… ﾊﾊ｡
That's why the place is in disarray.
Oh, so we're upper class now.
(新八)へ～
これで ﾎﾞｸらも ﾋﾙｽﾞ族ですか｡
That's amazing, Gin-san.
すごいですね 銀さん｡
銀さんは もう死んだって➡
Didn't I say that Gin-san is dead?!
言ってるだろ｡
社長と呼べ！ 社長と！
Call me President!
President, I say!
Hello, Sebastianita.
お～い ｾﾊﾞｽﾁｬﾝ子｡
茶は ﾜｲﾝはまだか｡
Where's the tea? The wine?
40年代ものがあったろ｡
Didn't we have a 40s vintage bottle?
はい 社長｡ どうぞ｡
Here, President.
You're very welcome.
おい 何だ？ これ｡
(神楽)ﾆﾛ ｱﾙ｡
Hey, what is this?
Nilo.
Of all choices, why Nilo?!
なんで よりによって ﾆﾛだ！
This isn't like having some
classmates over!
同級生遊びに
来てんじゃねえんだよ！
Nilo is a delicious and healthy beverage that
both children and adults should drink.
(神楽)ﾆﾛは おいしさと
栄養を兼ね備えた➡
子供は もちろん
大人も飲んでほしい １品ｱﾙ｡
ｵﾒｴが好きなだけだろ｡
ﾆﾛの回しもんか ｵﾒｴは！
That's only 'cause you like Nilo!
What, are you a spy for Nilo?!
ﾌｰ… ありがとうございます｡
Thank you very much.
え？
やっぱり おいしいですね ﾆﾛって｡
Nilo is always delicious.
ですよね～！
ﾆﾛって やっぱ最高ですよね！
Right?
Isn't Nilo the best thing ever?
すみません｡ 40年代ものの
ﾆﾛ用意してたんだけど…｡
I apologize.
I had some 40s vintage Nilo ready,
but she messed it up...
Mild.
ﾏｲﾙﾄﾞ｡
40年代ものの ﾆﾛって何だよ｡
What the hell would 40s
vintage Nilo be like?
(神楽)完全に舞い上がってるｱﾙ｡
He's getting way too excited.
ﾑﾘもないよ｡
結野ｱﾅは 銀さんの憧れ｡
You can't blame him.
Gin-san is a huge fan of Ms. Ketsuno.
He always had his eyes glued to the
screen for her weather forecast.
いっつも 天気予報
かじりつくように観てたんだから｡
I don't know how he managed to pick
her up, but what is he going to do?
どこで拾ってきたか知らないけど
どうするつもりｱﾙか？
天気予報当てるために
天気でも変えてやるいうｱﾙか？
Is she going to ask us to change the
weather so her forecasts are right?
いくら 万事屋でも ﾑﾘｱﾙ｡
That's impossible, even for us.
結野さん｡
Ketsuno-san.
残念ながら 私たちは➡
I'm sorry to say that it won't be possible
for us to change the weather for you.
あなたのために
天気を変えるなんてことは➡
さすがにできません｡
でも たったひとつ➡
But there is one thing we can do.
私たちにも できることがある｡
あなたの その雲り顔｡
Your gloomy face...
それを晴らすことです｡
We can clear it up for you.
社長 すいません｡ ﾌﾞﾗｲﾝﾄﾞないです｡
President.
Sorry to point out, but there's no blinds.
結野さん よかったら 私たちに
悩みを相談してみませんか？
Ketsuno-san, feel free
to tell us your worries.
きっと もう一度 あなたに
あの笑顔を取り戻してみせますよ｡
I'm sure we can put that
smile back on your face.
May I have another?
おかわり いいですか？
社長 すいません 聞いてないです｡
President.
Sorry to point out, but she isn't listening.
ﾆﾛで すでに
笑顔 取り戻してます｡
The Nilo has put a smile
back on her face.
その お気持だけで 十分です｡
I appreciate the thought.
There are still people cheering
me on after I've fallen apart.
こんなに ﾎﾞﾛﾎﾞﾛになっても
応援してくれる方がいてくれた｡
それがわかっただけで
私は 十分です｡
Just knowing that is enough for me.
なんだって
今まで読めていたものが➡
Why did you suddenly lose your
ability to forecast the weather?
急に
読めなくなっちゃったんですか？
いや… 今まで 占いで
天気当ててた時点で➡
I mean, the fact that you could predict the weather
through fortune telling was amazing enough...
すごいんですけど｡
何かあったんじゃないですか？
But did something happen?
相談して どうこうなる
問題じゃないんです｡
It's not an issue that can be
solved by talking about it.
ごめんなさい｡
やっぱり 何かあったんですね？
I'm sorry.
So something did happen.
話してください｡
Please tell us.
I don't want to put you in danger.
皆さんを 危険に
巻き込むわけにはいかない｡
危険？ どういうことですか？
そんなの聞いたら➡
Danger? What do you mean?
We definitely can't back
down after hearing that.
なおさら引き下がるわけには
いかないですよ！
結野ｱﾅ｡
Ms. Ketsuno.
私は 天気予報なんて
本当は 当たろうが当たるまいが➡
I don't care if your weather forecasts
are accurate or not.
どっちだっていいんです｡
私は ただ あなたの笑顔が
見たかっただけなんです｡
I just wanted to see your smile.
あなたの笑顔を見て
一日乗り切る元気をもらう｡
Your smile gives me the strength
to make it through the day.
ただ それだけのために
ﾁｬﾝﾈﾙをひねってた｡
That was the only reason
I turned to your channel.
毎日 毎日｡
Day after day...
今度は 私たちの番です｡
It's our turn now.
協力させてもらえませんか？
Will you let us help?
Is it really okay?
いいんですか？
For me to take advantage
of your kindness?
ﾎﾝﾄに 甘えちゃって…｡
You don't need to worry.
心配いりませんよ｡
こう見えても 私ども
腕っ節は立ちますから！
We're a lot tougher than we look.
ちょっとやそっとの危険なんて
ものともしません…｡
A little danger won't be any problem...
Tsk! They've found me!
ﾁｯ… 気取られたか！
God of the eastern sea, Amei!
東海の神 名は阿明｡
西海の神 名は祝良｡
God of the western sea, Shukuryo!
南海の神 名は巨乗｡
God of the southern sea, Kyojo!
北海の神 名は遇強｡
God of the northern sea, Gukyo!
Gods of the seas, repel the
fiends and halt this crisis!
四海の大神 百鬼をしりぞけ
凶災をはらう！
Evil be gone!
急々！ 如律令!!
Kyukyunyoritsuyou!
Um...
あの～ こういう感じなんですけど
ﾎﾝﾄに大丈夫ですか？
This is more or less what
you can expect.
Are you sure you're up for this?
Y-Yeah...
ああ… こ… こ…➡
S-S-So this is what we can expect, huh?
こういう感じね… うん はいはい｡
Right, gotcha.
こういうﾊﾟﾀｰﾝね｡ Ｂ２ﾊﾟﾀｰﾝね｡
So we're dealing with this pattern.
Pattern B2.
I-I-It'll be fine, yeah?
だ… だだ… 大丈夫だよな｡
全然 ｵｯｹｰだよな～｡
Perfectly okay, yeah?
うん
Ａ３ﾊﾟﾀｰﾝなら やばかったけど➡
Uh-huh, pattern A3 might have been
a problem, but we can handle this.
これなら いけるな？
いけるよな？
We can handle this, yeah?
いけるわけねえだろ～!!
何だ？ これ！
Hell no!
What is this?!
何だ？ 今のﾊﾞｹﾓﾉ！
なんで お天気お姉さんが➡
What was that monster?!
Why is the weather lady
fighting monsters?!
こんなのと戦ってんだ!!
天気予報➡
This has nothing to do with the weather!
ぜんぜん関係ねえだろうがっ！
私の天気予報が➡
You know that my weather forecasts are
done through fortune telling, right?
占いで行われていたのは
知ってますよね？
でも 本当は➡
But in reality, I wasn't doing anything
soft like fortune telling.
あれは占いなんて
甘っちょろいものじゃないんです｡
お天気お姉さんは 私の陽の顔｡
The weather lady is my morning facade.
でも私は
陰の顔も持っているんです｡
But I also have a different
identity at night.
Christel Ketsuno, the onmyoji.
陰陽師 結野ｸﾘｽﾃﾙ！
これが もうひとりの私の姿です｡
This would be the other side of me.
O-Onmyoji?!
おっ 陰陽師～!?
朝の顔のお天気お姉さんが
夜は 陰陽師!?
The morning weather lady
is an onmyoji at night?!
Yes.
そう｡ 陰陽師とは➡
Since ancient times, onmyoji, through
the teachings of the Mahabhuta,
古来より 陰陽五行説に基づいた
信仰によって➡
占術 呪術 祭祀を行ってきた
占いのｴｷｽﾊﾟｰﾄ｡
are experts of fortune telling through
divination, sorcery, and rituals.
In addition to revealing prophecy,
予知予言を 行うだけでなく
あらゆる災厄をしりぞけ➡
they were skilled sorcerers with the ability
conquer evil and stem disaster.
魔障を降伏させる力をもつ
呪術師なのです｡
私の一族は 徳川幕府開闢以来
江戸を守り続けてきた➡
Ever since the Tokugawa shogunate
was established, my family,
結野衆と呼ばれる➡
the Ketsuno clan, has been employed by
the Bakufu as onmyoji to protect Edo.
幕府お抱えの
陰陽師の大家なんです｡
なんで…
なんで そんなすごい人が➡
Why?
Why is someone so amazing
working as a weather lady?
お天気お姉さんなんて
やってるの!?
Why are you being attacked
by monsters?!
なんで あんなﾊﾞｹﾓﾉに
襲われなきゃならないの!?
このﾊﾞｹﾓﾉは 式神と呼ばれる➡
This monster is a shikigami, a sort
of familiar used by onmyoji.
陰陽師が使役する
いわば 使い魔です｡
つまり この式神は➡
In other words, an onmyoji sent this shikigami
to prevent you from assisting me.
あなたたちが 私に協力するのを
阻害するために➡
陰陽師によって
けしかけられたんです｡
そして 私の天道を読む力を
呪法でおさえつけ➡
And my ability to read the heavens has
also been repressed by an onmyoji.
天気予報のｼﾞｬﾏをしているのも
陰陽師の仕業｡
わかりますか？
Do you understand?
この江戸のどこかに➡
There is an onmyoji in Edo who doesn't
like the fact that I'm a weather lady.
私が お天気お姉さんを
やっているのが➡
気にくわない陰陽師がいるんです｡
And so, I will only be here a little longer,
ということで
残り少ないですけれども➡
最後まで
一生懸命がんばりますので➡
but I'll do the best I can until then.
よろしくお願いしま～す！
So please bear with me!
はい 結野ｱﾅ あと一週間
全力で がんばりましょうね！
Thank you, Ms. Ketsuno.
Do the best you can this final week.
それじゃあ
今日の天気 いってみようか？
Could you give us today's weather
then, Ms. Ketsuno?
結野ｱﾅ｡
今日の天気は➡
Today will be a sunny autumn day!
さわやかな秋晴れで～す！
えらいことになっちゃったｱﾙな
銀ちゃん｡
We've gotten into a crazy
mess, Gin-chan.
まさか 結野ｱﾅが
陰陽師だったなんて…｡
I never would have dreamed that
Ms. Ketsuno was an onmyoji...
おまけに 敵も陰陽師ときた｡
And she's up against another onmyoji.
((将軍や
お上のためなんかじゃない｡
It's not for the Shogun or the Bakufu.
私は…➡
I...
私は 市井の人々の笑顔のために
この力を使いたいから…))
I wish to use this power for the smiles
of the people in this town.
♪♪～
よし！ いくか｡
All right, let's get going.
えっ!? ちょっと待ってください！
Huh? Hold on a second.
いったい どこなんですか？ ここ｡
Where are we?
The Ketsuno clan are established
family of elitists.
結野衆は 由緒正しいｴﾘｰﾄ一族｡
そんな一族のなかに
たいした才能をもちながら➡
Yet one of their members chose
to become a weather lady,
お天気お姉さんなんぞになって➡
力を ﾑﾀﾞに使う者が出た｡
a waste of her considerable power.
権威で 頭の固くなった連中は➡
How do you think those stuffy
knuckleheads would feel?
これを どう思う？
まさか!?
You mean...?!
話つけにいこうじゃねえか｡
Let's go have a talk.
ｹﾂの穴にできた目障りな➡
With those assholes
ｲﾎﾞ痔どもと!!
and their hemorrhoids!
Wait, Gin-san!
待ってください 銀さん！
じゃあ ここが結野衆の!?
This is the Ketsuno clan residence?
ｴﾘｰﾄ陰陽師集団に➡
You're going to encroach on the territory
of an elite clan of onmyoji?!
殴り込みかけようって
いうんですか!? そんなﾏﾈしたら!!
If you do that...
なんじゃ 虫ｹﾗども｡
Who are you bugs?
ここを 結野衆の屋敷と知って
入ってきたのか～!!
You stepped in, knowing that this
was the Ketsuno clan's turf?!
あぁ～っ!!
I have no business with you tools.
ﾃﾒｴらみてえな
ちっちぇえ吹き出もんに用はねえ｡
Bring out the hemorrhoids.
ｲﾎﾞ痔出せ ｺﾗ～！
Or you want me to squeeze
some white puss out of you?
しぼって 白いｳﾐ
出されてえのか？ あ～ん？
Get the hell out of here
before we crush you!
踏み潰される前に
さっさと この場から消え去れ～!!
銀さ～ん!! やばいです！
殺されます 確実に!!
Gin-san! This is bad!
We'll get killed for sure!
ここは いったん帰りましょう！
作戦練り直して 出直しましょう!!
Let's leave for now!
Let's come back after we've
come up with a better plan!
な～に 怖気づいてんだ｡
心配いらねえよ｡
Why are you getting so scared?
There's no need to worry.
式神には式神を！
Fight shikigami with shikigami.
こっちも
ちゃんと用意してあんだよ｡
I've got my own here.
That's...?
それは… まさか！
That can't be...?!
結野ｱﾅから 護身用に預かった｡
Ms. Ketsuno gave this
to me as a precaution.
It apparently contains one of the
shikigami under her control.
これに 彼女が使役する式神が
封じ込められている｡
Really?!
ﾎﾝﾄですか!?
やい ﾃﾒｴら！
Hey, fools.
どうしても そこを
どかねえってんだな！
You'd better scram now, since I won't
be showing any pity afterwards!
あとで ほえﾂﾞﾗかいても
知らねえぜ!!
Come forth, Shikigami!
いでよ！ 式神～!!
(ｲﾝﾀｰﾎﾝ)
えっ？ ｲﾝﾀｰﾎﾝ？
An intercom?
すぐに
出てくるんじゃないんすか？
Aren't they usually supposed
to appear right away?
こういうのって…｡
Hey, what are you doing?
おい 何やってんだ｡
あぁ すみません｡
Ah, sorry about that.
ちょっと ちょっと
待ってください｡
Could you... Could you
give us a moment?
Gin-chan, try pressing it again.
銀ちゃん もう１回押してみるね｡
いでよ 式神！
Come forth, Shikigami!
(ｲﾝﾀｰﾎﾝ)
Yeah, this is definitely an intercom.
ほら やっぱりｲﾝﾀｰﾎﾝだ
ｲﾝﾀｰﾎﾝですよね これ｡
This is an intercom.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]はい｡
出た 誰か出ましたよ 式神？
Hello?
There! Somebody picked up!
A shikigami?
いでよ 式神！
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]あぁ ｳﾁ➡
Come forth, Shiki-
Ah, we already have a newspaper
subscription.
新聞もうとってるんでいいです｡
Uh, wait, no...
いや あのその…
新聞じゃなくて式神…｡
This isn't a sales pitch.
I'm asking for a shikigami...
Excuse me, but...
あの すみません
あの式神さんですよね？
You are a shikigami, correct?
An, Nakasaki-kun?
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]あぁ 中崎君かい ごめんね｡
Sorry, the shikigami is out right now.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]今 式神ちょっと出てんのよ｡
中崎？
Nakasaki?
Huh, you aren't the shikigami?
えっ？ 式神さんじゃないの？
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]ｽﾀﾔにﾋﾞﾃﾞｵ返しに行くって｡
Returning a video to Sutaya, I think.
[Note: "Sutaya" is a play on "Tsutaya,"
a large video store chain.]
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]帰ったら電話するように
言っておくから｡
I'll tell her to call back when she returns.
(電話を切る音)
Sutaya?
ｽﾀﾔ？ えっ 誰 今の｡
Huh? Who was that?
How many people are in this thing?
何人も この中にいるの？
ｽﾀﾔとかあるの？
They have a Sutaya?
Sounded like the mom.
お母さんっぽかったｱﾙ
いないんじゃ仕方ないね｡
We can't do anything if the
shikigami isn't there.
この際 お母さんでも
いいんじゃないすか？
Maybe the mom will do.
A shikigami's mom should
also be a shikigami, right?
式神のお母さんは式神でしょう｡
おい 何やってんだ
いい加減にしろよ｡
Hey, what are you doing?
Move on already.
Ah, sorry about that.
あぁ すみません
もう１回 もう１回だけやらせて！
One more time! Just one more time!
One last time then.
もう１回だけだぞ 早くしろよ｡
(ｲﾝﾀｰﾎﾝ)
Hurry it up.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]はい｡
あの 度々すみません｡
Hello?
Uh, sorry to bother you again.
I'm Sakata and I had an appointment
with the shikigami.
式神君と約束してた坂田ですけど｡
Ah, yes. Please wait one moment.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]あぁ はいはい
ちょっと待ってくださいな｡
All right! I think she's here this time.
やった 今度はいたらしいぞ｡
Hey, Father!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]ちょっと お父さん
お父さん ちょっと代わってよ｡
Father, take this call!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]また なんか変なの来てるわよ｡
It's another one of those funny people!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]ﾊﾞｼっと言ってやって
もうしつこい｡
Go tell him off!
Damn, you're loud...
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]んだよ うるせえな 中崎か？
Is it Nakasaki?
Him again? Cripes.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]また ｱｲﾂ来てんのか
仕方ねえな｡
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]はい 何!?
あの すみません｡
Hello? Whaddya want?
Ah, excuse me.
It's Sakata, not Nakasaki.
中崎じゃなくて坂田です
お父さんじゃなくて➡
And I was wondering if the shikigami,
not the father, is around?
式神さんいますか？
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]ｱﾝﾀか！
So you're the one who's been constantly
bugging our shikigami?
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]ｳﾁの式神に
しつこく つきまとってるのは!?
Will you cut it out?!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]いい加減にしろ ｺﾉﾔﾛｰ！
Uh, please listen to what I'm saying.
あの人の話 聞いてください｡
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]ちょっと待ってろ｡
Sit tight. I'm coming to smack you silly!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]今 ぶん殴りに行ってやっから｡
Yes, please do.
あぁ もう来てください
お父さんでいいから➡
The father will do.
Come on out already!
頼むから早く来てください｡
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]ｱﾝﾀ！
Hey!
Where are you going with that thing?!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]そんな物持って どこ行くの!?
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]黙ってろ！
Shut your trap!
I'm gonna deal with that Nakasaki
once and for all!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]今 中崎の野郎
黙らせに行ってやっから｡
Stop it!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]やめな！ 警察沙汰になるよ！
人 殺すつもりかい!?
You'll get in trouble with the cops!
You wanna become a killer?!
You're the one who told
me to deal with him!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]お前が何とかしろって
言ったんだろうが 離せ!!
Now let me go!
I said to stop!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]ﾀﾞﾒだって言ってんでしょ！
おい 危ねえぞ 大丈夫か？
Calm down!
Hey, this sounds dangerous!
Are they okay?!
(刺さる音)
H-Hey...
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]おい 節子…
どうしたんだ？ おい!!
Setsuko?
What's wrong?
Hey, Se-
えっ 何が起きてんの？
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]節子！
Huh? What's happening?
Setsuko!
Hey! What happened?!
おい なにがあった!?
どんなことになってんだ!?
What's going on there?!
What's with all the drama?!
何 勝手にﾄﾞﾗﾏﾁｯｸになってんだ！
刺さったｱﾙ｡
She's been stabbed!
They were grappling while he had a knife in
his hands and she ended up getting stabbed!
刃物持って もみ合ううち誤って➡
お母さん刺してしまったｱﾙ｡
えぇ!?
What?!
Hey! What are you doing?!
おい 何やってんだ！
知らねえ！ ｵﾚは何も悪くねえぞ!!
I don't know! I didn't do anything wrong!
Stop wasting time and summon
her so we can treat her!
もたもたしてないで
早く呼び出して手当てしてやれ！
えっ!? そっち？
でも あっちで➡
Huh?! That's your concern?!
Uh, but they might be treating
her on the other side!
手当てするかもしれねえし
そっとしといたほうが➡
Shouldn't we avoid moving
her around too much?!
いいんじゃねえのか？
いいから急げ！
Just hurry it up!
Uh, please!
頼む 誰か出てくれ！
(ｲﾝﾀｰﾎﾝ)
Someone answer!
Hello, this is the shikigami.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ](外道丸)はい 式神ですけど｡
出た！ 式神 ついに出た!!
All right! The shikigami finally answered!
Hey, there's some real
trouble going down!
おい 今やべえことに
なってんだけど そっちのほうが➡
Though the trouble's on your side!
やべえことになってるだろ？
今すぐ出てこい｡
Come out immediately!
お母さん連れて出てこい！
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ](外道丸)わかりやした｡
Come out with your mother immediately!
Understood.
Phew, we're safe now.
よかった これで万事解決だな｡
(外道丸)お待たせしたでござんす｡
I apologize for the wait.
式神 外道丸
ただいま参上つかまつりやした｡
The shikigami, Gedomaru,
is here at your service.
Sh-She's in mourning!
(みんな)喪に服してる！
Hey! We managed to summon
the shikigami,
おい！ 式神呼んだはいいけど➡
but the timing was horrible!
いったい どんなﾀｲﾐﾝｸﾞで
呼び出してんだ！
The funeral?!
葬式!?
葬式の最中に呼び出しちゃった!?
We called her out in the
middle of the funeral?!
And is that a picture of her mother?!
つうか あの遺影 お母さん？
お母さん もしかして➡
Did her mother end up dying?!
死んじゃった？ あれ!?
ｸﾘｽﾃﾙ様から➡
I have heard everything
from Lady Christel.
話は うかがっているでござんす｡
I am now Master Gintoki's servant
through blood pact.
血の契約により
これより あっしは➡
銀時様の僕｡
Feel free to order me around
as you please.
お好きに使っておくんなせえ｡
いや あのすみません｡
Uh, sorry.
ものすごく使いづらいんですけど｡
I find it really hard to order you around.
When your mind is clearly elsewhere.
心 ここにあらずだもの
完全に お母さんのこと➡
You're clearly thinking
about your mother.
引きずってるもの｡
Please don't feel bad about what
happened to my mother.
おっかさんのことは
どうか気に病まずに｡
あっしは 気にしてませんから｡
I don't hold it against you.
Don't feel bad?!
気に病まずって何？ 待って
ｵﾚが悪い感じになってんの!?
Why is she making it sound
like this was my fault?!
大丈夫でござんす
たとえ 親の仇であろうと➡
It's fine.
You may be responsible
for my mother's death.
主に従うが
式神の務めでござんすから｡
But I will fulfill my duty as a shikigami
and obey my master.
Don't make me sound
like the bad guy here!
人聞きの悪いこと言わないで！
I wasn't responsible for her death!
仇じゃないからね
ｵﾚ 何もしてないからね！
I didn't do anything wrong!
It's fine.
大丈夫でござんす
仕事とﾌﾟﾗｲﾍﾞｰﾄは➡
I don't mix personal and
business matters.
分けるﾀｲﾌﾟでござんすから｡
そういう問題じゃねえだろうよ！
No, that's not the issue here!
本当に大丈夫でござんすから｡
I'll really be fine.
Now, feel free to order me
around as you please.
さぁ 思う存分
こき使っておくんなせえ｡
おっかさん… 今すぐ
あっしもいくからね｡
Mother...
I'll join you in a minute...
How am I supposed to
order you around?!
使えるか!!
え？
Huh? What is the problem?
何が気にくわないで
ござんすか？
Uh...
いや ってか
やっぱりあの➡
And yeah...
遺影なんか持ってたら
闘いづらいし➡
Won't it be hard to fight while
holding that portrait?
第一 あの
使いづらい… なんか｡
And I mean, it's really difficult for
me to give you commands...
You know...?
ｵﾚたちも闘いづらいな｡
And it's pretty difficult for us to fight her.
いくら 敵でも
気い遣うっていうか｡
Even if we're enemies, we aren't
completely heartless...
いったん 置こうかそれ｡
Why don't you set it down for now?
闘うときくらいは
置いてもいいだろ｡
It should be okay to set it down
while you're fighting.
おっかさんを
地べたに捨て置くなんて➡
I could never place Mother
on the ground.
できないでござんす｡
じゃあ いったん預かろう｡
Then we'll hold it for you.
あの ちゃんとしたところに
たてまつっておくから｡
Uh, we'll place it in a proper location.
I apologize for the trouble.
申し訳ないでござんす｡
おっかさんを
よろしくお願いしやす｡
Please take good care of Mother.
いやいや 敵ながら
今どき珍しい｡
Don't worry about it.
It's rare to find such a daughter so devoted to
her parents, especially one who's an enemy.
親思いの優しい娘だ｡
ｵﾚの娘も
こんなんだったらねぇ｡
If only my daughter were the same...
Your belly's
(外道丸)腹が… がら空きじゃ!!
wide open!
(２人)え～っ!?
Huh?!
Y-You bitch!
き… ｷｻﾏ!!
You tricked us?!
たばかったか！
汚いﾏﾈを！
What a dirty trick...
Dirty?
汚い？ 誰にものを
申しているでござんすか｡
Who do you think you're talking to?
あっしは 外道を極めし鬼｡
I am the demon. Master of playing dirty.
Gedomaru.
外道丸でござんす｡
Exorcism complete.
調伏完了｡
か… かっけえ!!
She's so cool!
She killed them in an instant!
しゅ… 瞬殺した!!
あの強大な式神たちを！
An innocent little girl!
あの可憐な女の子が！
Against those huge shikigami!
And she killed them using
super dirty tricks!
しかも あんなに可憐なのに
とんでもなくど汚ねえ手で！
Stop standing around and let's get going.
(外道丸)ﾓﾀﾓﾀしてないで
行くでござんすよ｡
She stepped on it!
踏んだ！
お母さんの遺影 踏んだ!!
She stepped on the picture
of her mother!
お母さん？
Mother?
She died a thousand years ago.
そんなもの 一千年前に
とっくに死んでいるでござんす｡
すべて 猿芝居でござんす｡
芝居!? え ｲﾝﾀｰﾎﾝのくだりから？
It was all an act.
Act?!
Including the whole intercom bit?!
一人三役こなしてたんですか!?
You were playing three
roles by yourself?!
This is a shock.
(外道丸)ｺｲﾂは 驚いた｡
敵をあざむくため➡
I thought you were going along
with my act to fool the enemy,
芝居に つきあってくれていると
思いやしたが➡
本気で信じておりましたか｡
but you thought it was real?
銀時様 ひとつ
忠告しておくでござんす｡
Master Gintoki, I have a warning for you.
式神護法の類には➡
Shikigami are divided into loyal servants
術者が作りだした
根っからの従順な僕と➡
術者に調伏され
従わされている➡
and evil spirits, who are forced to
do the bidding of their master.
元は 悪鬼羅刹の
類があるでござんす｡
あっしは 後者｡
I would be the latter.
Caught by the Ketsuno clan when I was tearing
up Mt. Oe during the Heian period
平安の時代に 大江山で
暴れまわっているところを➡
結野衆によって調伏され 以来
結野家に仕えておりやすが➡
and forced to serve them ever since.
所詮は ただの化生の者｡
I am just another demon.
主に力なしと思えば
いつ 何どき➡
If my master shows any signs of weakness,
I may simply turn on him.
また 牙をむくかわかりやせん｡
夢々 お忘れめされるな｡
It would be best if you don't forget
that I am always watching you.
あっしが あなたを常に
見ていることを｡
あ あの… 誰か➡
U-Uh...
Anyone,
ｵﾚと 主かわんない？
ねぇちょっと 怖いんですけど!!
wanna be her master instead?
Hey! Wait!
I'm scared!
あの娘 なんか怖いんですけど｡
外道丸よ｡
She's really scaring me!
Gedomaru.
You are a servant of the Ketsuno clan,
結野衆に
仕える身でありながら➡
yet you have destroyed our shikigami
and trespassed on our territory.
その式神を破り
無断で屋敷に押し入るとは｡
いくら ｸﾘｽﾃﾙ様が式神とて
許されることではないぞ｡
You may be Lady Christel's shikigami,
but these actions cannot be forgiven!
Th-That's?!
あれは 結野衆!?
The Ketsuno clan?!
今のあっしは
ｸﾘｽﾃﾙ様ではなく➡
I no longer belong to Lady Christel.
I am this man's servant.
この男の僕でござんす｡
主が 何をするかはあっしの
知るところじゃございやせん｡
It is not my place to question
what my master does.
え!?
ｷｻﾏら まさか巳俚野家の!?
Huh?!
Could you be from the Shirino clan?!
(呪文)
Na maḥ sa maṃ ta va jrā nāṃ caṃ ḍa ma
hā ro ṣa ṇa spho ṭa ya huuṃ traṭ hāṃ māṃ.
Flames of Acala Vidyaraja!
不動明王火界呪！
すべての魔軍を焼き尽くせ!!
Incinerate all evil!
ｷﾞｬｰ!!
Gedomaru! Do some-
外道丸 何とかしろ！ ん？
Why are you hiding behind me?!
なんで ﾃﾒｴまで
ｵﾚの影に隠れてんだ！
(銀時たち)ｷﾞｬｰ!!
Did we get them?
やったか？
That is enough.
(晴明)そこまでにしておけ｡
この者たちは
ｸﾘｽﾃﾙの友人じゃ｡
These people are friends of Christel.
ｸﾘｽﾃﾙの友人は
ﾜｼの友人でもある｡
A friend of Christel is a friend of mine.
I will not permit any further
mistreatment of our guests.
これ以上 客人に
手荒なﾏﾈは許さんぞ｡
(晴明)この晴明が｡
Or my name isn't Seimei.
[Note: Name based on Onmyoji Seimei Abeno.]
[To Be Continued]
The next episode...
"Not Losing to the Wind."
Apparently so, big brother.
[Just who is the Seimei character who
rescued Gin-san and the gang?]
[Yes, Seimei is you-know-who's older brother!
(hint) It's not Kamotaro.]
[See you next time.]
♬『ゼッコーチョー！』
♬～